So, I have to admit something to you. I
have an addiction here. For the past
couple months, I've spent way too much
time building custom applications with
AI. The good news is that that totally
aligns with this YouTube channel, and I
get to show you various projects that I
do. So, in today's video, I'll be
showing you another one that solves a
problem that I genuinely deal with every
week. And the platform we'll be using
here has some standout features,
especially for people who haven't done
this before. Trust me on this, I've used
them all. But first, let's talk about
the problem I'll be solving here. So, as
you might know, I don't create these
videos by myself. Between the YouTube
channel, the community operations, and
the B2B training, at this point, we have
over 10 people scattered across the
world that are fully remote. This
creates time zone problems regularly.
And by now, I've just given up on this
idea of keeping track of all of it in my
head. And there's great apps that help
you convert one time zone to the others,
but I wanted something custom for our
team, something that the entire team can
use. And members, if they travel, like
our video editor that is in South Korea
right now, we can easily update. and
then see when we can schedule our
meetings in an instant. So, my goal
today is to build something similar to
this app that I really like, but custom
for our team. And I wanted to be visual,
too, so the team members can see where
we're across the globe cuz sometimes
working remotely can feel a bit
disconnected. And I told you I'll be
building this in quite the unique
platform. And at this point, if you're
following the channel, you might have a
similar feeling to me, which is that
there's many platforms that allow you to
build these applications from scratch.
But today, I'll be building it in base
44. And if you haven't heard of this,
they do one thing outstandingly well.
They have the most solid starting point
out of all these apps. And what I mean
by that is that you have everything that
you need at the beginning already
preconfigured. Authentication, a
database, user management, analytics,
domain management, and even a function
to run security checks on your site as
that is not even a consideration in most
VIP coding applications. And they've
reached out to sponsor a video. And as
per usual, we went ahead and tried it
and consulted our community. And what we
found is that there's actually multiple
people who actively use this who
absolutely love the fact that everything
just works from the get- go. And I'll
share a direct quote from one of our
members, Durk. He's like the vibe coding
guy in the AI advantage community. And
he said, "No other no code builder can
build complex applications in one shot
as well as this." And it makes sense
because it comes with so many pre-built
components. You can just build
applications without worrying about the
basics working. So with that being said,
let's get right into the build. We could
be using various templates here that you
can find up here which are obviously
great for inspiration, but we'll be
starting with a blank canvas right here.
And I prepared a little overview of what
we want to do here today. Just had a
simple little chat chy conversation
about my ideas and I got this and I
think it captures it really well. The
purpose of this aligns with what I told
you in the beginning. Basically, a world
map with various times and an option to
pick a future date and time to see what
that looks like for the various team
members. Here's a list of the various
team members and where they're located.
And what we'll do is we'll just copy
this over into base 44. I literally just
signed up with my Google account and
subscribed to the builder plan so I
could play with this. And that's it. I
didn't set up any external services.
None of that. This works really well at
streamlining all of that. And now I'll
just lean back for a second. I'll let it
do its thing. We'll time-lapse through
the building process and I'll see you in
a few minutes once this is done
building. And you have my words that we
didn't even do multiple takes. I'll just
show you what this creates on the first
try of the first recording. And as you
might already be able to tell, I do
expect this to be functional just
because Bass 44 is very consistent with
how it gets these things done. Okay, see
you in a second.
Oh, there it is. We got a little sound
notification. And let's review what we
got here. Oh, there's an issue. I can
just click this button, resolve with AI,
and it will do it. And again, I'll just
let this work and see where we get.
Okay. And there it is. We have a first
version of our application. So, let's
review this. So, I see a world map with
the various team members. That's me
right there. Yep. It's 2:14 p.m. That's
perfect. Then we have Daniel in the US,
Michael in Poland, and Robert in Korea
right here. So, this works like a charm.
Could even search team members. That's
good. Yeah, we can kind of look that up
like this. Perfect. There's a list view.
Okay, I would want to add the editing
capability here. And there's this future
time calculator here. And that seems to
work pretty well, too. I might just want
to add the world map here. But here's
the best part. You might expect this to
kind of work right off the bat in
various applications. But the unique
thing about B 44 is this. I could just
head on over to this dashboard. And this
is my default backend for the
application. And what I've been telling
you about before here, I could just
rename it quickly. Call it the AIA
Chronosync. Perfect. If I want to invite
users, I can just copy a link or send
invites via email like this. I can
change the visibility and you can
already see that by default it's public
and it requires login which means this
thing is already fully hosted for you.
If you just want to go ahead and share
this with people, I can go to share,
copy this URL and in the anonymous tab
you will see that this is live on the
web already and I can just continue with
Google and I already managed to log in.
Just as a reminder, all I did is just
send the prompt and hit fix with AI once
and we're at this stage already. That's
amazing. If I go to users, you can
already see the first account in here.
If I wanted to change anything in the
database, no need to use some external
application or learn something new. Just
if I travel out of Portugal, I could
change it in here as an admin. Preset
analytics are right here. If I want to
host it on my own domain or buy one, I
could do that here. And this security
tab is something that is just not
present in most of these. And although
this might not get you enterprisegrade
security, it checks for the most common
pitfalls. Like recently there was a big
leak of a vibe coded app where they
shared some of their secrets publicly
and this will check for it
automatically. You can start a scan like
this and then it makes a recommendation
to restrict the writing access for admin
users only and with the click of a
button it will apply those fixes and
there you go the security scan is
complete. If you want to get granular
you get all the code in here and there's
even an agents feature or API that is
automatically hosted from which you
could access this application from
within other apps. We'll talk about this
agents feature in a second here. But
before I do that, I just want to
highlight that you could take all of
this and just export it as a zip file
and then host it yourself, edit it
further if you decide to do so. But if
you just want to get things done, this
is incredible. So, let's get back to the
preview now that I've shown you the
dashboard and let's address some issues
here. So, I see when I log in now, the
map only partially loads sometimes and I
want you to add the nightday overlay and
I could send that. Alternatively,
there's also this visual edits thing
where I could have selected the element
and just edited that. But I think the
wording the map makes it pretty clear
which element I mean.
Okay, so did it. And if something
persists, as per usual with VIP coding
apps, you want to give it visual
context. So on a Mac with command shift
4, I screenshot this with command V. I
paste it in here. Make sure to add the
image. And this time I also select this
element.
Perfect. Fixed that. So I'll take a few
minutes to add a few features here that
we discussed. Then we'll review it. And
to round this out, I'll show you how to
integrate an AI agent into this process,
which is also super simple here. See you
in a sec.
All right. So, after a bit of back and
forth, the main thing I did here is
reorganize the tabs. Now, I have the
team view in a separate one, the map
view over here, and the future time
calculator is right below it. As this is
the main purpose of my app, I made one
customization, which is I added a
profile field. So, when you're logged
in, you can kind of self-edit your time
zone and your city. And I added a
profile picture uploads too. In this
view, the aspect ratio could be
different, but here on the map view, it
works perfectly. So, I can see right
here, this is me in Portugal. It shows
the time. And the same thing goes for
all other team members, even if they're
in Korea. And if I want to see if
another date works, I said this Friday,
and might want to do 30 minutes past
noon. And if I do that, it shows me the
other maps, but the night overlay
doesn't seem to work. So, I'll just
point that out and it'll fix it. But I'm
sure you understand that you can do that
at this point in time. Okay. So, to
round this out, I want to show you one
more really powerful feature. And that's
the fact that you can integrate AI into
these apps as simply as it could be
because every plan in B 44 includes
integrations which could mean sending
emails, sending WhatsApp messages, but
also calls to LLMs like chat GBT cla or
image generation and that can be
combined with their new agents feature.
So in other words, I could create this
agent that I can talk to that has
various tools that all just work. I
don't need to set up any API keys. It's
all connected already, which honestly is
rather rare. But let me just show you
this in practice. Here in the chat, I'll
type in something like create an agent
that allows users to change the team
database and update locations. And by
the way, for this to work, I need to
have AI agents enabled here in the
background. It's still in beta, but as
you can see right here, it just created
the very first team manager agent, which
has access to this person database
within my application. And then I could
use them as an admin or I could even
integrate it into the site and allow all
my team members to use that agent to do
things. and all from within the credits
that are included on the base 44
account. So the agent is right here and
I could look into it right now. There's
a short description and this prompt and
here in the tools you can see it has all
the access rights to our database. So
now I could follow up and say add the
agent as a new tab in the application.
Okay. And about 2 minutes later we have
a new agents tab up here. So let's go
ahead and just test this. So let's just
start a new chat and say eager is in New
York. It seems to have picked up the
chats from my previous tests of this as
I was trying this agent functionality
and it says I can't find anyone named
Eigor. So if I say list all users, it
shows everybody from the database
correctly and I'll just follow up by
saying Eigor Pagani is now in New York.
All right, now it's got the right entry
and I'll just say yes to this suggestion
as it can search the web and it does
that and then it finds the latitude,
longitude, country, all that from the
web and after final confirmation I can
update this data and now if I go to the
map view, Eigor should be in New York.
Yes, very nice. Look at that. And then
if I want to tweak this further, I could
obviously go here and for example, I
could remove this block that says always
confirm the change with the user before
executing them, making it mover to use.
And then also in here, you can kind of
update the various tools. You can see
that here it can access the database.
And they also have this WhatsApp
integration with more to come. But yeah,
there you go. That really shows you how
simple the AI integration into these
apps are. And that's yet another thing
that you would have to manage
externally. API keys, topping up that
account, creating separate databases for
authentication. None of that is needed
here. Base 44 really unifies everything
into one product. And I really, really
like that. You just get going and you
can quickly arrive at an application
like this. So this entire thing,
including the AI agent, has been built
in under an hour. And I think it's fair
to call this the most intuitive AI
builder out there. So if you want to
build a custom application with AI,
there's no simpler way to do it than
with B 44. And I genuinely mean that. It
solves all the common problems that you
will run into. So go ahead and try today
and with the code advantage 10, you can
start building immediately. All right,
that's all I got for today. My name is
Igor and I will see you very